

Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

 $\underline{www.LondonResearchInternational.com}$

Mr. Mortimer

NATIONALITY: South Africa

SUMMARY

During the past 20 years I have gained extensive experience in a variety of environmental fields, starting as a specialist in pure Nature conservation and progressing to consulting as a specialist in ecology, botany and biodiversity. The last eight years have been spent, almost exclusively, in the construction and/or mining and minerals fields as either a consultant or in a management role. My last posting was that of Environmental Superintendent at Bisha Mining (Eritrea) but for the bulk of the two and a half years in the position I served as the Acting or Mentor Manager to both the locally appointed Environmental Manager and the identified successor to the Superintendent post.

My areas of expertise include the following:

- I am able to communicate effectively at all levels required for both internal and external liaison.
- Strong academic and practical application background, with extensive knowledge of my field.
- Excellent, proven management skills to ensure effective and efficient use of resources.
- Able to implement strategies and policies to optimize operational performance.
- Solutions-focused problem solver, who combines past experience with new knowledge.
- Computer literate.

EDUCATION

National Diploma

Pretoria Technikon, 1992

Certificate

Pretoria Boys' High School, 1987



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com

 $\underline{www.LondonResearchInternational.com}$

EMPLOYMENT RECORD/ PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Environmental Superintendent

Bisha Mining Share Company - April 2011 to January 2014

Dates Positions Companies

04/2011 - present Environmental Superintendent Bisha Mining Share Company

• Environmental Officer

SENET Construction - May 2009 to March 2011

• 03/2011Environmental Officer

SENET Construction EPCM - May 2009 to May 2009

Eritrea

Senet, as EPCM contractor, constructed the CIL Gold plant infrastructure for Bisha Mining Share Company.

• 07/2008 - 04/2009 Specialist Environmental Consultant

RPM Eco Services (owner) Pretoria

Provided specialist terrestrial ecology-, biodiversity- and botanical assessments for a variety of clients including mining and property developers.

Key Projects:

- o Game farm management plans
- Limpopo-Lipadi Game and Wilderness Reserve, Botswana; Dombeya Safaris,
 Vaalwater; WhêKwê
- Safaris, MusinaVegetation assessments
 - Woody species assessment and mapping for Richmond Platinum Mine and Steelpoort Der Brochen
 - Welverdiend (Bambisana Project) for property development EIA purposes,
 Piet Retief
- Terrestrial ecological assessments
 - Kendal Siding for development and mining purposes
 - VanDyksdrift proposed coal mine expansion project
- Biodiversity assessment including provision of plan and mitigations
- VanDyksdrift, DMO Project



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

 $Email: \underline{consultant@londonresearchinternational.com}\\$

 $\underline{www.LondonResearchInternational.com}$

07/2007 - 06/2008 Specialist Environmental Consultant

SAS Environmental Pretoria

Scientific Aquatic Services (SAS) provides specialist input to EIA practitioners who do not employ such specialists, as well as an in-house GIS mapping and delineating capability.

Key Projects:

- Terrestrial ecological assessments for EIA purposes
 - Property developments: Alicedale, Eastern Cape; Bronhorstspruit;
 Burgersfort; Hazyview;
- o Naboomspruit; Sani Pass Hotel, KZN; Scheerpoort.
 - Water bottling plant: Coca Cola water bottling plant (Heidelberg)
 - o Mine development: Twin Rivers Platinum mine; Mooihoek mine
- Vegetation Assessments
 - Siyabuswa pipeline for EIA purposes
 - Floral assessment with emphasis on location of Red Data species and provision of mitigation
- measures (proposed river crossing on coal mine).
- o Biodiversity assessments including plan for the following:
 - Modikwa Platinum Mine, Steelpoort; Xstrata Alloys, Rustenburg; Mooihoek Mine.
- o Terrestrial ecology and red data assessments
 - Olympus AH, portion 81 and Olympus AH, portion 84.

On top of these experiences above, I have been working as Environmental Officer since 1992.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS	
n/a	
PUBLICATIONS	
n/a	
LANGUAGES	

English